

36 E, Ambagaha Junction Road, Wellampitiya

🛮 (+94) 0719250289 | 🗷 sabiqsabry48@gmail.com | 🖸 sabiqsabry48 | 🛅 sabiqsabry48 | 💆 @sabiqsabry48

"seek discomfort"

Summary _

Current Senior Web Developer at a start-up company called Tnaidar. 2+ years experience specializing in the frontend and backend development and infrastructure automation. Super nerd who loves Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Skills

Proficient: HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, Angular, React, NodeJS, Java, Python, Flutter, React Native, Git, Github

Exposure: **MySQL**, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, TS, C++, C, Ajax, Ruby Other: **sweet Problem Solver**, Communication, Leadership

Work Experience

the Radiant.

Thimbirigasyaya, Colombo 05

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Jan. 2021 - May. 2021

- · Provisioned an easily manageable hybrid infrastructure(Amazon AWS + On-premise) to maintain order towards the whole company and orders.
- Built fully automated Invoice form and contract programs.
- Designed an overall service architecture and pipeline of an Artificial Intelligence Program to be run on the site soon
- Implemented several API microservices in Node.js towards client needs.
- · Deployed a centralized monitoring environment in regularity towards staff

UniqSolutions Borella, Colombo 08

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Implemented RESTful API server for car rental booking application(Gaman which was later a failed approach) using PHP
- Built and deployed overall sample programs for POS systems made using C
- Developed an easy-to-use employee status tracker using IOT technologies.

Clickbuy Dematagoda, Colombo 09

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Jan. 2018 - current

- Handled the business's online presence regularly.
- Implemented a platform to track customer orders.
- · Currently working on the UI of the site.

MiTechSolutions

Bambalapitiya, Colombo 04

HARDWARE ASSISTANT

March. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- Evaluated interfaces between hardware and software
- · Advises customers regarding maintenance of software system

Kent InstituteWellampitiya, Colombo-Greater

Conducted classes for Cambridge and National O-Level and A-Level Students on the IT and Computer Science stream.

• Currently conducting online classes on Computer Science for both O-Level and A-Level students during the weekend.

Education

TEACHER

IIT(Institute of Information Technology)

Wellawatte, Colombo 06

Sep. 2018 - current

Jul. 2015 - current

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Gone through Foundation.
- Completed basic Web Development front-end and back-end modules.
- Taking up electives in Quality Assurance.

LIS(Lyceum International School)

Wattala

STUDENT 2006 - 2016

- Got through GCE O/L in 2016
- President, IT Society

Honors & Awards

20203rd Place, Datathon Competition FinalSLIIT, Malabe20175th Place, HackathonSLIIT, Malabe20132nd Place, Inter-school Presentation Competition FinalLyceum, Wattala

Projects

| 2021 | ONCO , an application built using Flutter infusing Machine Learning models for Cancer Treatment | https://git.io/JsEZD |
|------|--|----------------------|
| 2019 | Online Cart System (Store) - YOLO, a site which shows a simple customer purchase system using javascript | https://git.io/JJ0uB |
| 2020 | Amirah Gems, an E-commerce site for an upcoming jems and jewellery company called Amirah | amirahgems.com |
| 2020 | Sri Lankan Cricket.lk, a site about the Sri Lankan cricket team and live matches | https://git.io/JTFjh |
| 2020 | MidWestEdu, a site for a college which includes online sign up register forms and such | midwestedu.lk |
| 2020 | Masjid Al Maqbool, a landing page made using React for a mosque in Sri Lanka which includes registration | masjidalmaq- |
| | forms for masjid events | bool.com |